ARE YOU READY, KIDS?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids:
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
孩子们：
是的，是的，队长！
I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
我听不到你说话。
( louder ):
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
（大声）：
是的，是的，队长！
* OH... *
* 哦... *
* WHO LIVES IN A PINEAPPLE
UNDER THE SEA? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS! *
* 海绵宝宝！ *
* ABSORBENT AND YELLOW
AND POROUS IS HE. *
* 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的。 *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS! *
* 海绵宝宝！ *
* IF NAUTICAL NONSENSE BE
SOMETHING YOU WISH... *
*如果航海废话是
您想要的东西... *
* SPONGEBOB SQUARE PANTS! *
* 海绵宝宝方形裤子！ *
* THEN DROP ON THE DECK
AND FLOP LIKE A FISH. *
* 然后掉到甲板上
像鱼一样扑通扑通。 *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS! *
* 海绵宝宝！ *
* READY?
SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS! *
* 准备好？
海绵宝宝！ *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS! *
* 海绵宝宝！ *
( laughs heartily )
（会心地笑）
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
( plays airy tune )
[字幕由THE赞助
美国教育部
（演奏轻快的曲调）
and NICKELODEON]
和尼克频道]
MRS. PUFF'S BOATING SCHOOL
太太。普芙划船学校
WHERE DILIGENT STUDENTS LEARN
THE RULES OF THE ROAD.
勤奋的学生学习的地方
交通规则。
Mrs. Puff:
EVERYONE
泡芙女士：
大家
PUT DOWN YOUR BOOKS
放下你的书
BECAUSE IT'S TIME TO PICK OUT
THE HALL MONITOR OF THE DAY!
因为是时候选择了
当今的大厅监视器！
LET'S SEE HERE.
让我们看看这里。
THIS WEEK'S HALL MONITOR
WILL BE...
本周大厅监控
将会...
BART, JIMMY, NO, NO
巴特，吉米，不，不
TINA, RALPH, HMM... ( gasps )
蒂娜、拉尔夫、嗯……（喘气）
( in quaking voice ):
SPONGEBOB.
（声音颤抖）：
海绵宝宝。
( chair squeaks )
（椅子吱吱作响）
IT'S JIMMY.
这是吉米。
JIMMY'S THE HALL MONITOR.
吉米是大厅监视器。
MRS. PUFF, I'VE DONE IT ALREADY.
太太。噗，我已经做到了。
( chair squeaks )
（椅子吱吱作响）
OH-- PHIL?
哦——菲尔？
NO WAY,
MRS. PUFF.
没办法，
夫人。噗。
UH, TINA--
YOU'RE THE HALL MONITOR.
呃，蒂娜——
您是大厅监控员。
HEY, I'VE DONE IT
THREE TIMES ALREADY.
嘿，我已经做到了
已经三次了。
( chair squeaks )
（椅子吱吱作响）
B-BETH...
B-贝斯...
Boy:
SHE GRADUATED.
男孩：
她毕业了。
HENRY! ( squeak )
亨利！ （吱吱声）
VERA! ( squeak )
维拉！ （吱吱声）
CLAYTON!
克莱顿！
( chair squeaking
repeatedly )
（椅子吱吱作响
反复）
( sighs )
（叹气）
ALL RIGHT, I GUESS
I HAVE NO CHOICE.
好吧，我猜
我别无选择。
( gulps )
（咽了口口水）
THE HALL MONITOR OF THE DAY
IS...
当今的大厅监视器
是……
OH... SPONGEBOB.
哦...海绵宝宝。
YA...HOO!
呀...呼！
HALL MONITOR SPONGEBOB
霍尔监视器海绵宝宝
REPORTING
FOR DUTY, MA'AM.
报告
为了职责，女士。
I'M READY
TO ASSUME MY POSITION
我准备好了
担任我的职务
IN THE HALL.
在大厅里。
I WILL PROTECT ALL
THAT ARE WEAK... IN THE HALL.
我会保护所有人
大厅里的人很弱。
ALL RULES WILL BE ENFORCED...
IN THE HALL.
所有规则都将得到执行...
在大厅里。
OKAY!
好的！
JUST TAKE THE HAT AND BELT.
只需带上帽子和腰带即可。
I CAN'T ACCEPT
THAT YET, MA'AM.
我不能接受
到目前为止，女士。
I HAVE TO MAKE MY SPEECH.
我必须发表演讲。
YOU CAN'T MAKE THIS EASY,
CAN YOU?
你不能让这变得容易，
你可以吗？
CLASSMATES!
同学们！
WHO AM I TO DESERVE
SUCH A GREAT HONOR?
我值得谁
这么大的荣誉？
WHY, I WOULD
BE NOTHING
为什么，我会
什么都不是
WITHOUT MRS. PUFF.
没有夫人。噗。
GIVE ME A BREAK.
让我休息一下。
AND TO MY PUBLIC
以及我的公众
ALL I CAN SAY IS I'M TOUCHED.
我只能说我很感动。
AND FURTHERMORE
而且更进一步
I WILL CARRY
OUT MY DUTIES...
我会携带
我的职责...
CRIME AND PUNISHMENT,
PUNISHMENT AND CRIME
罪与罚，
惩罚与犯罪
IN THE HALL.
在大厅里。
WHICH REMINDS ME
OF AN EXTREMELY
LONG SPEECH
这让我想起了
一个极端的
长篇演讲
WRITTEN BY THE
GREATEST HALL MONITOR
撰写者
最伟大的大厅监听器
OF ALL TIME.
有史以来的。
"FRIENDS, STUDENTS,
JUVENILE DELINQUENTS
“朋友们、学生们，
少年犯
LEND ME YOUR EARS."
把你的耳朵借给我。”
( snoring )
（打鼾）
IN CONCLUSION
AND WITHOUT A MOMENT TO SPARE
结论
一刻不停
I WILL PUT ON THIS UNIFORM
AND ASSUME MY DUTIES AS...
我会穿上这件制服
并承担我的职责...
HALL MONITOR!
大厅监视器！
WISH ME LUCK, MRS. PUFF.
祝我好运，夫人。噗。
OH, AND I WILL BE...
哦，我会...
( bell dings )
（铃声响起）
SPONGEBOB, ARE YOU OKAY?
海绵宝宝，你还好吗？
I OVERDID THE SPEECH AGAIN,
DIDN'T I?
我又夸夸其谈了，
我不是吗？
I'M AFRAID SO.
我恐怕是这样。
AW, TARTAR SAUCE!
哇，鞑靼酱！
I GUESS I WON'T BE NEEDING THIS.
我想我不需要这个。
I HARDLY KNEW YE.
我几乎不认识你。
UH... SPONGEBOB?
呃……海绵宝宝？
YES, MRS. PUFF?
是的，夫人。噗？
I CAN AT LEAST LET YOU
WEAR IT UNTIL TOMORROW.
我至少可以让你
穿着它直到明天。
YAHOO!
雅虎！
THANKS, MRS. PUFF.
谢谢，夫人。噗。
WHAT ARE THE CONSEQUENCES
OF WHAT I'VE JUST DONE?
后果是什么
我刚刚做了什么？
( shudders )
（颤抖）
( sighs )
（叹气）
( humming )... HALL
（嗡嗡声）...大厅
( humming )... MONITOR.
（嗡嗡声）...监视。
( humming )
（嗡嗡声）
( horns honking )
（喇叭鸣响）
BROKEN TRAFFIC LIGHT.
交通灯坏了。
WHO'S TO SAY
MY MONITOR DUTIES SHOULD END
谁说的
我的监控职责应该结束
JUST BECAUSE THE BELL RANG?
就因为铃声响了？
I CAN BE HELPFUL ANYWHERE.
我可以在任何地方提供帮助。
THIS LOOKS LIKE A JOB
FOR THE HALL MONITOR!
这看起来像是一份工作
对于大厅监视器！
( blows whistle )
（吹口哨）
( blowing whistle rhythmically )
（有节奏地吹口哨）
WHAT WOULD THIS TOWN DO
WITHOUT YOU, SPONGEBOB?
这个小镇会做什么
没有你，海绵宝宝？
Man:
MY LEGS!
男士：
我的腿！
MY LEGS!
* ON PATROL *
* 巡逻 *
* I'M ON PATROL... *
* 我正在巡逻... *
UH-OH, AN OPEN WINDOW.
呃-哦，一扇打开的窗户。
MORE SEAWEED MEDLEY,
DEAR?
更多海藻杂烩，
亲爱的？
THE FOOLS.
傻瓜们。
THEY'VE LEFT THEMSELVES
SUSCEPTIBLE TO DANGER.
他们离开了自己
容易受到危险。
I MUST SHOW THEM
THE ERROR OF THEIR WAYS
我必须向他们展示
他们的做法所犯的错误
THROUGH EXAMPLE.
通过例子。
( SpongeBob screams )
（海绵宝宝尖叫）
I'M THE OPEN WINDOW MANIAC!
我是开窗狂人！
( both screaming )
（两人都尖叫）
I HOPE YOU LEARNED
A VALUABLE LESSON!
我希望你学到了
宝贵的一课！
* ON PATROL *
* 巡逻 *
* I'M ON PATROL *
*我在巡逻*
* I'M ON PATROL... *
* 我正在巡逻... *
( gasps )
（喘气）
VANDALS!
破坏者！
ANOTHER CRIME.
另一种犯罪。
( smacking his lips )
（咂嘴）
HMM... STRAWBERRY.
嗯...草莓。
I MUST ACT.
我必须采取行动。
PATRICK...
帕特里克...
PATRICK!
帕特里克！
MY ICE CREAM-- IT'S ALIVE!
我的冰淇淋——它是活的！
( screams )
（尖叫声）
PATRICK, DOWN HERE.
帕特里克，在这儿。
OH, SPONGEBOB, IT'S YOU.
哦，海绵宝宝，是你。
PATRICK, COME DOWN HERE.
帕特里克，下来。
SPONGEBOB...
海绵宝宝...
SPONGEBOB!
海绵宝宝！
I'M DOWN HERE.
我在这儿。
YOU LOOK FUNNY.
你看起来很有趣。
HI, SPONGEBOB.
嗨，海绵宝宝。
THAT'S "HALL MONITOR"
TO YOU.
这就是“霍尔监视器”
给你。
SORRY, OFFICER.
对不起，警官。
SORRY'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH,
PATRICK.
抱歉还不够好，
帕特里克。
YOU'VE JUST
COMMITTED A CRIME
你刚刚
犯罪
AND I'M TAKING YOU IN.
我要带你进去。
WHAT CRIME?
什么犯罪？
I'M A BAD PERSON.
我是个坏人。
( sobbing )
（抽泣）
Newspaper boy
( in high voice ):
EXTRA! EXTRA!
报童
（高声）：
额外！额外的！
MANIAC STRIKES
BIKINI BOTTOM!
疯狂的罢工
比基尼泳裤！
CITY PARALYZED WITH FEAR!
城市因恐惧而瘫痪！
( in gruff voice ):
TELL YOUR FRIENDS.
（粗声粗气）：
告诉你的朋友。
ARM YOURSELVES
WITH KNOWLEDGE.
武装自己
凭借知识。
EXTRA! EXTRA...
额外的！额外的...
HMM... "MANIAC...
BIKINI BOTTOM...
嗯……“疯子……
比基尼泳裤...
CAR WRECKS... BREAK-IN."
车祸……闯入。”
WHO BETTER TO BRING
THIS MANIAC TO JUSTICE
最好带谁
将这个疯子绳之以法
THAN ME...
THE HALL MONITOR!
比我...
大厅监视器！
BUT I CAN'T HANDLE
THIS CASE ALONE.
但我无法处理
仅此案。
PATRICK,
ARE YOU READY
帕特里克，
你准备好了吗
TO GIVE UP
YOUR LIFE OF CRIME?
放弃
你的犯罪生涯？
I WANT TO BE GOOD!
我想成为好人！
HMM... NOW YOU JUST NEED
A SYMBOL OF AUTHORITY.
嗯......现在你只需要
权力的象征。
PERFECT.
完美的。
IT IS OUR DUTY
TO CATCH THIS MANIAC
这是我们的责任
抓住这个疯子
AND BRING HIM TO JUSTICE.
并将他绳之以法。
BUT HOW TO PROCEED?
但如何进行？
LISTEN, DEPUTY,
YOU'RE AN EX-CRIMINAL--
听着，副手，
你是一名前科犯——
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
你会怎么办？
HMM...
唔...
I'D GET AN ICE CREAM.
我要一个冰淇淋。
( both licking loudly )
（两人都大声舔）
OKAY, NOW WHAT?
好吧，现在怎么办？
HMM...
唔...
THIS ISN'T WORKING.
这是行不通的。
WE'VE GOT TO DO
SOMETHING ELSE.
我们必须做
还有别的事。
SOMETHING WITH...
WALKIE-TALKIES!
一些与...
对讲机！
( squeals )
（尖叫声）
AND NOW DUTY CALLS.
现在是值班。
ALL RIGHT, DEPUTY,
I'LL GO THAT WAY
好吧，副手，
我就那样走
YOU GO SOME
DIFFERENT WAY.
你去一些
不同的方式。
GERONIMO!
杰罗尼莫！
( imitates police siren )
（模仿警笛）
( police siren approaching )
（警笛靠近）
( tires squeal )
（轮胎吱吱声）
AFTERNOON, SON.
下午，儿子。
HELLO, BROTHERS.
哈喽，兄弟们。
SON, WE'RE LOOKING
FOR THE MANIAC.
儿子，我们正在寻找
对于疯子来说。
HAVE YOU SEEN THIS MAN?
你见过这个人吗？
( screams )
（尖叫声）
IT'S THE MANIAC!
这就是疯子！
TAKE HIM AWAY,
TAKE HIM AWAY.
把他带走，
把他带走。
CALM DOWN, SON,
IT'S JUST A DRAWING
冷静点，儿子，
这只是一张图
NOT THE REAL THING.
不是真实的东西。
NOW WE'RE
GOING TO SHOW YOU
现在我们是
将向您展示
THIS PICTURE AGAIN
AND YOU'LL TELL US
又是这张照片
你会告诉我们
IF YOU'VE SEEN
THIS GUY, UNDERSTAND?
如果你见过
这家伙，明白吗？
YEAH, UH-HUH.
是啊，嗯。
OKAY.
好的。
( screams )
（尖叫声）
HORRIBLE!
可怕！
( screams again )
（再次尖叫）
( stops and starts
screaming repeatedly )
（停止和开始
反复尖叫）
STAY INDOORS, SON.
呆在室内，儿子。
AND TAKE THAT CONE
OFF YOUR HEAD.
拿走那个圆锥体
摆脱你的头脑。
( both chuckle )
（两人都笑了）
SPONGEBOB.
海绵宝宝。
Come in, SpongeBob.
进来吧，海绵宝宝。
Answer!
回答！
SPONGEBOB HERE, PATRICK.
海绵宝宝在这里，帕特里克。
REPORT.
报告。
I don't want to be
a policeman anymore.
我不想成为
不再是警察了
I'm scared.
我很害怕。
GET A HOLD OF YOURSELF, DEPUTY.
控制住自己，副手。
( Patrick sobbing )
（帕特里克抽泣）
I want to go home!
我想回家！
POOR ROOKIE.
可怜的菜鸟。
ALL RIGHT, I'M ON MY WAY BACK.
好吧，我正在回来的路上。
HURRY, SPONGEBOB.
快点，海绵宝宝。
I THINK IT'S GETTING...
我认为它正在变得……
DARK.
黑暗的。
JUST PUT ON YOUR SIREN,
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
只要拉上你的警笛，
我马上就到。
( imitating weak siren )
（模仿弱海妖）
( imitating loud siren )
（模仿响亮的警笛声）
SPONGEBOB, I SEE HIM.
海绵宝宝，我看到他了。
WHERE IS HE, PATRICK?
他在哪里，帕特里克？
AT THE INTERSECTION
OF CONCH AND CORAL.
在十字路口
海螺和珊瑚。
SpongeBob:
THAT'S WHERE I AM.
海绵宝宝：
这就是我所在的地方。
HE'S RIGHT ON TOP OF ME,
BUT I CAN'T SEE HIM.
他就在我上面，
但我看不到他。
WHAT'S HE DOING?
他在做什么？
UH... HE'S JUST
STANDING THERE...
呃...他只是
站在那里……
MENACINGLY!
威胁性的！
Get out of there, SpongeBob!
离开那里，海绵宝宝！
YAAH!
啊啊！
THAT'S HIS MANIAC SHRIEK.
这就是他的疯狂尖叫声。
HE'S GOING TO ATTACK.
他要进攻了。
( whining and sobbing )
（呜咽和抽泣）
He's acting all crazy.
他表现得很疯狂。
RUN!
跑步！
Hide behind that building.
躲在那栋大楼后面。
No, he's behind that building.
不，他就在那栋大楼后面。
Quick, hide behind
that street sign.
快躲到后面去
那个路牌。
No, wait!
不，等等！
The maniac just went
behind that sign.
疯子刚刚走了
那个标志后面。
Quick, get under
the street light.
快点到下面去
路灯。
No! wait!
不！等待！
He's there, too!
他也在那儿！
Run for your life!
为你的生命而奔跑！
( screaming )
（尖叫）
( sighs )
（叹气）
( muffled radio transmission )
（低沉的无线电传输）
SAY AGAIN, DEPUTY?
再说一遍，副手？
THE MANIAC'S IN THE MAILBOX.
疯子在邮箱里。
( screams )
（尖叫声）
( screaming and babbling )
（尖叫声和胡言乱语）
HUH-- THIS GUY'S NOT
HALF-BAD-LOOKING FOR A MANIAC.
嗯——这家伙不是
看起来有点像个疯子。
WAIT A MINUTE, PATRICK.
等一下，帕特里克。
I'M THE MANIAC.
我是疯子。
( Patrick screams )
（帕特里克尖叫）
( sirens wail )
（警报声）
WE'LL TAKE THAT AS A CONFESSION.
我们会把这当作一种忏悔。
SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS,
THERE YOU ARE!
海绵宝宝，
你在那里！
I TURN MY BACK ON YOU
FOR ONE MINUTE
我转身背对你
一分钟
AND YOU DESTROY
HALF THE CITY!
而你摧毁了
半个城市！
YOU SHOULD BE ASHAMED
OF YOURSELF.
你应该感到羞耻
你自己。
YOU KNOW
THIS GUY?
你知道
这个家伙？
OF COURSE I DO.
我当然愿意。
I'M THE ONE WHO GAVE HIM
THE UNIFORM IN THE FIRST PLACE.
我是赐予他的人
首先是制服。
HE'S MY RESPONSIBILITY.
他是我的责任。
UH-OH.
呃-哦。
Mrs. Puff:
AND IN CONCLUSION, STUDENTS
泡芙女士：
总之，学生们
RED MEANS STOP,
GREEN MEANS GO.
红色表示停止，
绿色意味着前进。
AND SPONGEBOB...
还有海绵宝宝...
YES, MRS. PUFF?
是的，夫人。噗？
I'D LIKE TO SEE YOU
AFTER CLASS
我想见你
课后
SIX MONTHS FROM NOW.
六个月后。
( door slams )
（关门声）
AH, JELLYFISH FIELDS.
啊，水母田。
HERE WE FIND SPONGEBOB
ONCE AGAIN
我们在这里找到海绵宝宝
再次
STALKING THE WILD JELLYFISH.
追踪野生水母。
SPONGEBOB?
海绵宝宝？
HELLO? SPONGEBOB?
你好？海绵宝宝？
HMM-- HE'S SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE SOMEWHERE.
嗯——应该是他
来到这里的某个地方。
AHA!
啊哈！
( jellyfish buzzing like a bee )
（水母像蜜蜂一样嗡嗡作响）
SAFETY FIRST.
安全第一。
AHA!
啊哈！
I FINALLY GOT YOU.
我终于找到你了。
( splatting )
（溅）
( jellyfish moos )
（水母哞哞叫）
( buzzing )
（嗡嗡声）
( with French accent ):
AH, THERE IS NOTHING BETTER
THAN THE TASTE
（带有法国口音）：
啊，没有比这更好的了
比味道
OF NATURAL JELLY
FROM A JELLYFISH.
天然果冻
来自水母。
SEE YOU LATER!
稍后见！
OH... OH, MY GLASSES.
哦...哦，我的眼镜。
THANKS, LITTLE GUY.
谢谢，小家伙。
BYE.
再见。
I CAN'T PLAY ANYMORE, JELLYFISH.
我不能再玩了，水母。
I GOT TO GET HOME.
我得回家了。
NO, YOU CAN'T COME HOME WITH ME.
不，你不能和我一起回家。
( steps squeaking
like SpongeBob's )
（脚步吱吱作响
就像海绵宝宝一样）
JELLYFISH,
YOU'VE GOT TO STAY HERE.
水母，
你必须留在这里。
( buzzing )
（嗡嗡声）
HEY!
嘿！
STAY!
停留！
STAY...
停留...
( jellyfish giggling )
（水母咯咯笑）
JELLYFISH, FOR THE LAST TIME,
YOU CANNOT COME HOME WITH ME!
水母，最后一次，
你不能和我一起回家！
AW, WHAT THE HECK.
噢，到底是什么？
SQUIDWARD, HEY, SQUIDWARD!
章鱼哥，嘿，章鱼哥！
SQUIDWARD!
章鱼哥！
SQUIDWARDIARD!
鱿鱼王！
SQUIDWARD, LOOK AT MY NEW PET.
章鱼哥，看看我的新宠物。
THAT'S NO PET,
THAT'S A WILD ANIMAL.
那不是宠物，
那是野生动物。
NO, HE ISN'T.
不，他不是。
WATCH THIS.
注意这个。
FETCH.
拿来。
HOW MANY FINGERS
AM I HOLDING UP?
有多少根手指
我坚持住了吗？
( hums deeply
three times )
（深深地哼了一声
三遍）
PLAY DEAD.
假死。
( bell tolls )
（钟声）
I WOULDN'T LET THAT THING
IN MY HOUSE
我不会让那件事
在我家里
EVEN IF IT WAS POTTY-TRAINED.
即使它受过如厕训练。
( humming casually )
（随意哼哼）
I DIDN'T NEED TO SEE THAT.
我不需要看到这个。
WELL, WE'RE GOING
TO MY HOUSE
好吧，我们走了
到我家
TO HAVE A LITTLE FUN.
享受一点乐趣。
HOW CAN YOU POSSIBLY HAVE FUN
WITH A JELLYFISH?!
你怎样才能玩得开心
与水母？！
( techno music
with heavy bass playing )
（科技音乐
重低音演奏）
* HEY! *
* 嘿！ *
( techno music
continues blasting )
（科技音乐
继续爆破）
SPONGEBOB IS THE ONLY GUY I KNOW
海绵宝宝是我唯一认识的人
THAT CAN HAVE FUN
WITH A JELLYFISH...
那可以很有趣
与水母...
FOR 12 HOURS!
12 小时！
UGH... WOW!
呃...哇！
YOU SURE LIKE TO DANCE.
你肯定喜欢跳舞。
WELL, THAT'S ENOUGH FOR TONIGHT.
好了，今晚就够了。
IT'S TIME TO GO TO BED.
是时候去睡觉了。
( jellyfish buzzing )
（水母嗡嗡声）
( music blasting )
（音乐震耳欲聋）
HUH?
嗯？
YOU'VE GOT IT ALL WRONG,
LITTLE FELLOW.
你都错了，
小家伙。
( music starts again )
（音乐再次响起）
BED!
床！
REPEAT AFTER ME, "BED."
跟着我重复一遍，“上床”。
( buzzing )
（嗡嗡声）
WE'LL JUST KEEP YOU RIGHT HERE.
我们会让您留在这里。
( meows )
（喵）
QUIT WORRYING, GARY.
别担心，加里。
HE'LL BE JUST FINE.
他会没事的。
GOOD NIGHT, EVERYBODY.
大家晚安。
( snoring )
（打鼾）
( droning loudly )
（大声嗡嗡声）
( snoring )
（打鼾）
( meows )
（喵）
( buzzing gibberish )
（嗡嗡作响的胡言乱语）
( meows )
（喵）
( giggling )
（咯咯笑）
( meows )
（喵）
( rooster crows )
（公鸡打鸣）
MMM... GOOD MORNING, GARY.
嗯……早上好，加里。
GOOD MORNING, JELLYFISH.
早上好，水母。
JELLYFISH?
海蜇？
HERE, JELLYFISH!
在这里，水母！
OH, JELLY!
哦，果冻！
( meows wetly )
（湿漉漉地喵喵叫）
OH, JELLYF...
哦，果冻……
( yelling )
（大喊）
( techno music playing )
（电子音乐播放）
WHERE'D YOU ALL COME FROM?
你们都是从哪里来的？
OKAY, THAT'S IT.
好的，就是这样。
PARTY IS OVER!
派对结束了！
YOU GUYS HAVE OVERSTAYED
YOUR WELCOME.
你们已经逾期居留了
欢迎您。
THIS MUSIC IS WAY TOO LOUD.
这音乐太大声了。
( screams )
（尖叫声）
VERY FUNNY.
很搞笑。
I'M SERIOUS.
我是认真的。
( rumbling and crackling )
（隆隆声和噼啪声）
( grumbling )
（抱怨）
18 HOURS!
18小时！
I'M GOING TO GIVE THAT
SPONGEBOB A PIECE OF MY MIND.
我要给出这个
海绵宝宝是我的心声。
( phone ringing )
（电话铃声响起）
( garbled ):
HELLO.
（乱码）：
你好。
SpongeBob,
listen to me
海绵宝宝，
听我说
you square-headed
assault on my ears.
你方头
攻击我的耳朵。
I'VE HAD ENOUGH OF THIS!
我已经受够了！
STRAWBERRY.
草莓。
TWO CAN PLAY AT THIS.
两个人可以玩这个。
( inhales deeply )
（深吸一口气）
COME ON, GUYS
来吧，伙计们
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
够了。
HUH?
嗯？
( clarinet playing squeaky
version of "Row Your Boat" )
（单簧管演奏吱吱作响
《划你的船》的版本）
( screams )
（尖叫声）
HEY, TAKE IT EASY! OW!
嘿，别紧张！噢！
OKAY, I'LL TALK TO HIM.
好的，我会和他谈谈。
SQUIDWARD,
WOULD IT BE POSSIBLE
章鱼哥，
有可能吗
TO PLAY YOUR CLARINET
A LITTLE... BETTER?
演奏你的单簧管
稍微……好一点？
I DON'T THINK
THE JELLYFISH LIKE IT.
我不认为
水母喜欢它。
THE JELLYFISH DON'T LIKE...
水母不喜欢...
WHA... WHY SURE, PAL,
I CAN PLAY BETTER.
哇...为什么当然，朋友，
我可以打得更好。
OKAY, HE SAID HE'LL PLAY BETTER.
好吧，他说他会打得更好。
( Squidward inhales deeply )
（章鱼哥深吸一口气）
( playing loud, blaring note )
（大声演奏，响亮的音符）
UH-OH, THAT'S NOT BETTER.
呃-哦，那不是更好。
HEY, TAKE IT EASY WITH THAT!
嘿，别着急！
( playing gurgly rendition
of "Row, Row, Row Your Boat" )
（播放咕咕的演奏
的“划，划，划你的船”）
( clarinet squeaks )
（单簧管吱吱声）
Squidward:
UH, WAIT--
I CAN TURN IT DOWN.
章鱼哥：
呃，等等——
我可以把它关掉。
( Squidward yelling,
electricity crackling )
（章鱼哥大喊，
电噼啪声）
( knock at door )
（敲门）
EVERYBODY'S A CRITIC.
每个人都是批评家。
YOU WON'T BE HEARING
FROM ME ANYMORE.
你不会听到
不再是我了。
HEY, NOW, THAT WASN'T NICE.
嘿，现在，那不太好。
( boat horn blows )
（船喇叭吹响）
OKAY, THAT IS IT!
好的，就是这样！
EVERYBODY OUT!
大家都出去！
( groaning )
（呻吟）
( groaning again )
（再次呻吟）
( music stops )
（音乐停止）
( gulps )
（咽了口口水）
( buzzing )
（嗡嗡声）
UH, WAIT... HOLD ON.
呃，等等……等等。
UH, WAIT.
呃，等等。
OW, OW...
噢，噢……
OW, OW, OW...
噢，噢，噢……
( yelling )
（大喊）
( electricity crackling )
（电噼啪声）
( yelling )
（大喊）
COME ON, GARY.
来吧，加里。
( deep rumbling )
（深沉的隆隆声）
GARY, YOU WERE RIGHT.
加里，你是对的。
THANKS FOR NOT RUBBING IT IN.
感谢您没有摩擦它。
( buzzing loudly )
（大声嗡嗡声）
( teeth chattering )
（牙齿打颤）
( clicking )
（点击）
HUH?
嗯？
THEY STOPPED?
他们停下来了吗？
( clicking )
（点击）
GARY, DON'T STOP SHAKING IT!
加里，别停止摇晃！
( jellyfish humming peacefully )
（水母安静地嗡嗡作响）
( gurgling in tempo )
（节奏中咯咯作响）
( rattling in tempo )
（节奏嘎嘎作响）
( clicking in tempo )
（按节奏点击）
( playing bass riff )
（演奏低音连复段）
( singing )
（唱歌）
( slide guitar playing )
（滑音吉他演奏）
( trumpets join in )
（喇叭加入）
( clicking )
（点击）
( everybody strumming,
clicking, rattling or singing )
（大家都在弹奏，
咔哒声、嘎嘎声或歌唱）
TODAY SPONGEBOB HAS LEARNED ONE
OF THE SEA'S HARSHEST LESSONS--
今天海绵宝宝学会了一个
大海最惨痛的教训——
WILD ANIMALS CAN THROW
VERY WILD PARTIES.
野生动物可以扔东西
非常疯狂的派对。
( screeching with pain )
（痛苦地尖叫）
OOH, I FELT THAT.
哦，我感觉到了。
[Captioning sponsored by THE
and NICKELODEON]
[字幕由THE赞助
和尼克频道]
[Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[标题为
字幕中心
WGBH教育基金会]
[标题为
字幕中心
WGBH教育基金会]